Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adopted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
I can cut a thousand strands of hair
but I cannot sever the tangled threads of my mind.
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For all the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For all the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Peace and auspiciousness to My Lady.
What is this place?
We are at the side entrance of the Shunzhen Gate.
The side entrance?
Only Her Majesty the Empress may use the main gate.
Concubines may only use the side entrances.
Meizhuang!
My Lady, you will have time to talk later.
You will now be led to your palaces and chambers.
The Household Department has delivered
your baggage to your residences.
Please follow us and enter the palace.
In which palace will Attendant Sourire live?
The Palace of Pearl Jade.
Worry not, My Lady. Please go with them.
Attendant Sourire, please follow me.
Companion An, please follow me.
Lady Shen, please follow me.
It's splendid!
No wonder everyone wants to come to the Forbidden City.
My Lady, the soaring wild geese are an omen of good luck.
I hope you don't mind hastening a bit. It's a distance away.
Peace to My Lady.
You may rise.
Thank you, My Lady.
My Lady, this is your residence, the Chamber of Brilliance.
Thank you, sir.
Sir, please treat yourself to a cup of tea.
Thank you, My Lady.
Please enter.
It's more deserted the further we walk.
Not at all, it's a peaceful place.
That's what My Lady prefers.
My Lady, this is your residence.
Thank you, sir.
We'll take our leave.
How did you get in?
What a small palace for enemies!
A mere Companion, aren't you?
Companion An, everything's ready in your chamber.
Attendant Services has delivered your baggage.
Greetings, Miss Xia.
No.
Don't you address me like a friend!
You'll taint me with the sour smell of poverty.
Peace to Attendant Xia.
That's the proper etiquette.
My Lady, let's go to your room.
My Lady, this is your palace.
Looks very nice. It seems newly renovated.
It was.
The palace was assigned to
Lady Parfum after His Majesty's coronation.
His Majesty ordered the renovation.
So we are living with Lady Parfum?
Please, My Lady.
Attendant Sourire arrives.
I bow before My Lady.
Peace to My Lady.
You may rise.
It was a long trip. Please have a good rest, My Lady.
We will take our leave.
Thank you, sir.
My Lady, I hope you like your palace.
We cleaned it thoroughly from early morning.
Palace of Pearl Jade.
An exquisite name.
My Lady, this is the main chamber,
with two side chambers on its east and west.
Behind it, there's a bedchamber and a garden.
On the south side, sits the Chamber of Verdant Immersion.
A refreshing summer residence.
This palace was named for its pear flowers,
which look like falling pieces of jade.
And the crabapple trees bear bright red flowers.
They look very festive.
Why is there a stage?
There are many theaters in the palace
to entertain the concubines.
This one became less frequented due to its distance,
so it was built into a residence.
How do you like the palace, My Lady?
It's very calming indeed.
My Lady, Her Majesty the Empress
had the sweet olives planted for you.
She wishes you a sweet and auspicious life in the palace.
Exactly.
That was very thoughtful of Her Majesty.
Please enter the main chamber, My Lady.
Your palace's head eunuch, Kang Luhai
bows before Attendant Sourire.
May peace and auspiciousness be with you, My Lady.
Your palace's head maid, Cui Jinxi
bows before Attendant Sourire.
May peace be with you, My Lady.
Please rise.
- Yes.
- Thank you, My Lady.
I was told that Lady Parfum lives here as well.
I should pay respects to her right away.
My Lady, Lady Parfum does not live here any more.
Her west chamber is vacant.
Attendant Chun moved into the east chamber four days ago.
Naturally she will visit you later.
My Lady, this is Xiao-Yunzi.
These two are apprentices of Mr. Kang:
Xiao-Hezi and Xiao-Yinzi.
These are your maids: Violet and Daisy.
They are all in your service solely.
May peace and grace be with you, My Lady.
From today on, you will be under my name.
While I appreciate you being smart and competent,
above all else, I value your loyalty.
Yes. Yes.
Is that understood?
My Lady, we pledge to have steadfast loyalty and undivided faith.
Go ahead.
We'll be at your service, My Lady.
Would you like to have a rest after the tiring trip?
Yes, you may leave.
Yes. Yes.
Madam Cui, you must have been in the palace for a while.
My Lady, please call me by my humble name: Jinxi.
Madam, please stand.
I've never grown accustomed to the rules.
Although you are in my service,
you are my elder and more experienced in the palace.
I hold great respect for you.
I'm not worthy of your courteous words, My Lady.
I used to serve a concubine of the prior emperor.
She preferred to have fewer maids and reassigned me.
With such an extended service in the palace,
you must be a reliable person.
I'm flattered, My Lady.
I'll have to trouble you and Mr. Kang from now
to take care of my palace matters.
My Lady, I will spare no effort.
Please go have a break.
Vermilion and Jade will take over.
I take my leave, My Lady.
Let's all sit. What a stressful day!
There were a whole lot of rules!
It was so scary.
But the room's so nice.
Be watchful of the rules, not only the room.
I brought you two into the palace.
You must be extremely careful of your speech and manners.
Of course!
Vermilion just needs to control her quick tongue.
You're annoying!
She has a sharp tongue, but it doesn't hurt.
She knows what to say and what not to.
You two grew up with me together
and have now moved into the palace with me.
Living here is like walking along a cliff with our eyes covered.
If we can't trust those around us, we can fall into ruin at any time.
If one of us rises or falls, so will the others.
You treat us like your sisters, My Lady.
Jade and I will protect you at our best.
I will take good care of you both as well.
Please don't worry, My Lady.
Your Majesty has been reading all morning.
Would you like to have some tangerines?
The new concubines must have settled in by this hour.
Yes, they have ensconced themselves in their palaces.
I can finally have some time to myself
while Consort Fleur takes care of the palace.
She's the only one Your Majesty should worry about.
There were excellent pomelos offered as tribute,
but Songzhi took them and gave us the tangerines.
She claimed that her palace deserves the best
because His Majesty will have lunch there.
And last time,
when Suzhou Clothing Services supplied textiles,
her palace was the first to choose.
These are minor matters.
What's the harm in letting her have her way?
The peonies in the yard look a bit askew.
Tell the gardeners the compact the soil,
so the blossoms will come back in the spring.
But Your Majesty...
Her Majesty is the Mother of the Nation.
Why should Her Majesty be bothered?
Where's Vermilion?
My Lady, you ordered our kitchen to make some pastries
to send to Lady Shen and Companion An.
Vermilion has just got on her way to deliver them.
My Lady, Madam Autumn sent gifts to you
on behalf of Her Majesty the Empress.
You are required to greet Her Majesty in the
Palace of Great Benevolence at the fourth hour in three days.
I understand.
Also, the head eunuch of the Palace of Earthly Honor,
Mr. Zhou, is waiting outside.
Palace of Earthly Honor?
That's Consort Fleur's palace.
I see.
- I will be there shortly.
- Aye.
My Lady, Consort Fleur is on a par with Her Majesty.
You cannot show any disrespect.
It's very nice to see you, sir.
Please.
Peace to Attendant Sourire.
Thank you for waiting, Mr. Zhou.
Her Highness Consort Fleur sends you some gifts.
I thank Her Highness for her generous thought.
Please extend my gratitude to Her Highness.
Would you like to sit down for some tea, sir?
I regret to decline your kindness, My Lady.
Her Highness has strict rules on us.
I have to visit other concubines.
I'm afraid I must go now.
Thank you for coming, sir.
My Lady, if there's nothing else I can help you with,
I will take my leave.
Congratulations, My Lady.
Her Highness showed great appreciation for you.
These won't come into use for the time being.
Please keep a record and put them in the storeroom.
Yes.
My Lady, you received as many gifts as Lady Shen.
In Companion An's palace,
only Lady Fuca and Attendant Xia received gifts.
Consort Fleur sent generous rewards.
She must be trying to win over the new concubines
based on their backgrounds.
Peace to Attendant Xia.
Madam Autumn, you shouldn't have visited personally.
Please come in!
Her Majesty was hoping all new concubines can settle in comfortably.
So she sent me to check on everyone.
And to also bring over some textiles,
which are the tributes from Southern Clothing Services.
Her Majesty favors me and sent you to visit me personally.
I am extremely flattered!
It's my pleasure. Allow me to take my leave.
Take care, Madam.
Goodbye, My Lady.
Don't fault others for ignoring you.
You were born poor and humble.
Are those all the miserable gifts you received?
Consort Fleur's gifts are good,
but incomparable to Her Majesty's.
Make a dress with the textile from Her Majesty in three days.
I will thank Her Majesty in that dress
when the harem pays respects to her.
Don't be bothered by Attendant Xia, My Lady.
My humble being carries no weight.
She wasn't wrong.
Don't lose heart, My Lady.
Your origin doesn't determine your future.
My Lady, Attendant Chun is here.
Please come in!
(Attendant Chun)
You had a busy day, Sourire.
Hope I'm not disturbing you!
Not at all. I was just thinking about visiting you.
But you're here already.
Have a seat.
Jade, serve some tea.
Yes.
I have Pu'er tea for today. I hope you like it.
You have so many tasty pastries here.
I didn't eat enough at dinner. Can I have some pastries first?
I'll have the tea later to wash down the starch.
Go ahead!
Vermilion, bring more pastries.
Yes.
It's so good!
You look very young.
No, I'm fourteen.
You don't seem to like like Pu'er ...
Jade, make milk tea.
Yes.
Thank you, Sourire. I love sweet food.
Take your time, don't get choked.
Please call me Chun'er.
That's what my parents call me.
Sure.
Was there something wrong with your dinner?
I was missing home.
The Imperial Kitchen made wine-soaked goose,
and I remembered that my mother's is the best.
So I felt homesick.
Come here if you don't eat well the next time!
Can I?
You're so nice to me!
I heard His Majesty really likes you.
When I saw the courtyard packed with people
rushing in gifts this afternoon,
I knew it must be true.
I received some lovely flower hairpins.
Take some if they catch your eye!
It's all right...
I like... your pastries more.
Eat as much as you want.
Jade, wrap up some good ones
and send them to Attendan Chun's chamber.
Yes.
Thank you, Sourire.
Lotuses are harvested south of River Yangtze....
The Imperial Garden was surely a feast for the eyes.
Everything was so finely arranged.
What a lowborn woman!
Are you not able to sew without humming a siren's song?
You cannot serve His Majesty overnight for these three days.
But when that day arrives,
won't you sing your way to His Majesty's bed?
I was singing mindlessly.
Attendant Xia, I will stop if you don't like it.
Don't give me that pitiful face!
I didn't ...
When you finally see His Majesty one day,
if you ever can,
don't you dare be a minx like this!
Not on my watch!
Who does she think she is?
Always acting this way.
My Lady, don't lower yourself to be like her.
Forget it.
She's here, so I'll go out.
Let's go visit my friends.
It smells so good,
doesn't it?
Let's get another one.
Hey, you're here. Come on in!
You should have announced the arrival of Lady An!
How could you let her wait in the sun?
Don't scold him, Sourire. I asked him not to.
I didn't want to interrupt, but it's my fault you were disturbed nonetheless.
It was thoughtless of me.
You have no fault, only good intentions.
Huan'er, you're to blame. You scared Lingrong.
You owe her an apology over tea.
Please come in for tea. Come in.
I went to Meizhuang's palace first,
hoping to come here together with her.
But she had already left. I came late.
It's not late at all. We can all catch up now that you're here!
The head of my palace, Concubine Estime,
is very kind and easy to talk to.
How about your palace?
It's... not too bad.
Lady Fuca seems all right.
But Attendant Xia...
I will stay away from her.
I will spend more time with you two.
My Lady, you are always welcome here.
I know you don't like Lu'an tea,
so I prepared jasmine tea for you.
After I lived for a few days at your home,
Jade was troubled to remember all my preferences.
You both treat My Lady as your sister.
I must serve you as best I can.
I thought Vermillion was the quick-witted one.
But Jade has a honeyed mouth and an attentive heart.
Jade has been with me all these years.
Naturally, she became more perceptive.
Of course, our dowry maids know us the best.
I moved in with Lunar and Stellar.
Lingrong, you didn't bring a dowry maid.
How are the servants in your palace?
Coua is a competent maid. I can always count on her.
I have two other maids.
They are just fifteen years old, and not as dependable.
But don't worry, I've always been able to take care of myself.
Jinxi.
Yes.
Please report to Her Majesty that I will send Daisy to
serve Companion An in the Palace of Prolonging Happiness.
Yes.
Daisy is young but very well-trained.
She will go back to your palace with you.
Don't hesitate to tell us if you need anything else.
Thank you, Sourire.
The textiles I received today seem suitable
to be made into dresses for you.
Lunar will bring them to your palace later.
Both of you have been so kind to me.
I don't know how I can ever repay you.
I will be eternally grateful for your friendship and help.
We three know each other well and came to the palace together.
It's natural we care for one another like sisters.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
My Lady, today is your first time to pay respects to the Empress.
You should dress nicely to stand out.
Please bring me some hot water.
Jade will help me get dressed.
Yes.
Do my hair as usual.
Understood.
Your Highness, it's time to leave for the Palace of Great Benevolence.
We can't be late today.
There's no hurry.
Your Highness is uniquely styled.
The phoenix coiffure looks exceptionally distinguished.
[Phoenix is equivalent to the emperor's dragon]
We'll go.
Our new sisters have all arrived so early.
How does everyone find living in the palace?
I thank Your Majesty for asking. All is well.
I hope I'm not late.
Peace to Consort Fleur.
Peace to Your Majesty.
Please rise.
Consort Fleur came in late. Were you feeling unwell this morning?
His Majesty was working late last night,
so I accompanied him for a little longer.
This morning, His Majesty insisted that I get some more rest.
That caused my delay.
I hope it's all right with Your Majesty.
His Majesty has been tirelessly occupied at court
and may have overlooked you.
That's why he was making it up to you.
Since we welcome the new concubines today,
there will now be more companionship for you.
Consort Fleur made quite an entrance.
Who's she trying to impress?
(Jiang Fuhai)
The new concubines will formally bow to Her Majesty.
May grace and peace be with Your Majesty.
All rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
You will now greet the other concubines.
Her Highness Consort Honnête is unwell
and won't receive your greetings today.
Her health is not improving.
Autumn, please visit her after the ceremony.
Yes, Your Majesty.
The new concubines will greet Consort Fleur.
Peace and grace to Your Highness.
The jadeite we received this year is overly light in color.
It lacks quality.
Fine jadeite is becoming increasingly rare.
You are too young for dark-colored jadeite.
Naturally, the Household Department selected
the fresher colors appropriate to your age.
After all, I believe that only the finest jadeite
was selected for the imperial family.
Of course, I've always considered jadeite too mature.
Not suitable for me.
If Your Majesty doesn't mind their quality,
I should give my jadeite earrings to Your Majesty.
I have recently received a pair of eastern pearls
and had them made into these earrings.
I'm afraid I shall not be extravagant.
His Majesty wouldn't appreciate that if he knew.
I admire Your Majesty's frugality.
All right, you should let them rise.
Oh, I was so absorbed in conversing with the Empress.
All rise.
I thank Your Highness.
I've heard that Attendant Xia is quite capable.
Peace to Your Highness.
I am the Attendant from the Xia family.
You are very well-attired.
Your dress must be expensive.
This was made from Her Majesty's awards.
I'm wearing it for this special occasion today.
That's very thoughtful.
You are a grateful recipient of favors.
Rise.
I thank Your Highness.
And which are Lady Shen and Attendant Sourire?
Shen Meizhuang from the Palace of Universal Happiness
bows before Your Highness.
Zhen Huan from the Palace of Pearl Jade
Lady Shen carries an air of elegance.
And Attendant Sourire's modest dress cannot hide her beauty.
His Majesty has a keen eye to discern the real pearls.
All right, you may rise.
I thank Your Highness.
Your Highness has "the face of a peony"
and truly captivating beauty.
We are pale as candlelight
when compared to the radiance of Your Highness.
That is very sweet of you, Lady Shen.
But the phrase "the face of a peony"...
Isn't it only appropriate for describing an Empress?
Her Majesty is as beautiful as a mudan peony
[the type of peony that is associated with an empress]
while Your Highness has the splendor of a shaoyao peony.
We are incomparably inferior.
Now we have even more sweethearts in the palace.
Every one of you is certainly sweet and intelligent.
Residing in the palace, not only should you serve His Majesty
wholeheartedly and expand the imperial family,
but also live in harmony and unity.
You must not displease His Majesty
with any conflicts and jealous rivalries.
Yes.
Jiang Fuhai, is the Empress Dowager expecting us?
The Empress Dowager extended her delight over the new concubines' arrival
and acknowledged their wishes to pay her respects.
Her Majesty is paying homage to the Buddha.
Your Majesty need not lead the concubines
to the Palace of Longevity.
I understand.
You all must be tired. You may kneel and take leave.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
That was quite a show! You both have a way with words.
You ingratiated yourselves with Consort Fleur
right after pleasing the Empress.
It was like watching two actors on a stage.
How I admire your skills!
Peace to Attendant Xia.
You have a brigade of servants carrying your gifts.
Is there enough space in your palace for all these awards?
The imperial favors should be shared among the entire family.
I was just thinking of having the quality items
distributed among the other concubines.
Since you are already here,
why don't you be the first one to choose?
Please have a look, Attendant Xia.
My family is never lacking such trinkets.
But I can see that Lady Shen
is very good at winning over people's hearts.
How could someone with her manners be selected?
Her head is no more than an empty vessel.
The Xias are not even worthy of carrying shoes for our Nian family.
I've heard that she has caused much chaos in the Palace of Prolonging Happiness.
She has been a bother to Lady Fuca
and giving Companion An a hard time.
You see her dress.
Does she think she can swagger around the palace
wearing the Empress's favor on her back?
Attendant Xia, I heard that you come from a valiant and noble family.
My family has generations of gallant warriors serving the nation.
How can a village magistrate compare to us?
My offense on the Selection day was unintentional.
I have reflected upon it with deep remorse.
I believe, given your family upbringing,
you must have an outstanding martial heritage.
I was impressed by your demeanor, like a soldier.
You honor your family's noble reputation.
I must live up to my family's teaching.
It's baffling to find such foolishness under Heaven.
And she was granted the title of Attendant.
Did she "attend" school at all?
Stop!
You cannot beat a concubine of His Majesty!
Let go!
Peace and grace to Your Highness.
Your Highness.
- Zhou Ninghai.
- Yes.
It's all right.
The Imperial Garden in autumn is as lovely as a painting.
But my peaceful stroll has been disrupted.
How disappointing!
Companion An verbally offended me.
I only wanted to discipline her.
No offense meant.
Are neither I nor the Empress any longer in the palace?
I didn't know that Attendant Xia had taken over the household
and the responsibility of disciplining concubines.
I'm afraid this is too much of a burden to bear.
The maple trees are not vibrantly red this year.
Your Highness, I heard that the maple leaves
become truly stunning when dyed with fresh blood.
Is that so?
I shall reward Attendant Xia with "Three Yards of Red".
So that her blood can add crimson hues to the maple leaves.
"Three Yards of Red"?
My Lady is not aware.
"Three Yards of Red" is a penalty in the palace.
Your lower waist will be beaten with wooden boards
that are two inches thick and five feet long.
Until the flesh and bones are blurred with blood.
It appears a brilliant, flowing red even from a distance.
Hence the name "Three Yards of Red".
My Lady, please proceed.
Your Highness... Please spare me, Your Highness.
I will never do it again, Your Highness.
Please spare me, Your Highness.
My Lady, it would be a blessing from past lives
if your blood can truly add color to the imperial trees.
Please spare me, Your Highness.
Take her to the Imperial Department of Penalty.
Xia disrespected her peers and superior concubines.
I hope she didn't give you a scare.
Although "the law doesn't punish the masses,"
the three of you were also involved.
She implicated herself by her own actions,
but you three are not exempt from being punished.
Reflect on yourselves behind closed doors.
It made my blood run cold.
Although Xia is foolish and arrogant,
her actions didn't warrant such a penalty.
I've heard of Consort Fleur's power,
but never expected her to be so ruthless.
Consort Fleur asked us to reflect on our actions...
It is merely a time for reflection. Don't be afraid.
We should go back to our palaces now. I'm scared.
Let's go.
What happened?
What is going on?
There ... There is ...
Speak calmly. Don't frighten us.
Yes...
My Ladies, I was ordered to check
the water levels in garden wells.
But in that well ... I saw...
I'll take a look.
You shouldn't. It might be something foul.
I'll just have a look. Don't worry.
What is it?
Don't go...
It's a dead body.
Your Majesty, it was Fuzi.
Her body was found in a well.
Fuzi?
How could she end up dead in a well?
I have no idea. The well is located out of the way.
Of course, you wouldn't know.
I ordered Fuzi to serve Consort Fleur.
Rise.
I will inquire about it in Consort Fleur's palace.
There is one more thing.
Speak.
Consort Fleur punished Attendant Xia
with "Three Yards of Red".
Xia misbehaved. She has to face the consequences.
What a pity Fuzi has lost her life to unknown causes.
She was an innocent maid.
I couldn't find her anywhere!
Understood. Go, go.
My Lady, where have you been?
We've been looking for you.
Why do you look unwell, My Lady?
Please sit down.
My Lady, Jiang Fuhai came to deliver a decree from the Empress.
Starting from tomorrow, the new concubines
can expect to serve His Majesty.
Congratulations, My Lady!
You will definitely be the first to receive His Majesty's favors.
Not necessarily tomorrow, My Lady,
but you should be prepared.
Yes. Yes.
Are you feeling hungry, My Lady?
Ask them to serve the meal immediately.
No need.
I have no appetite.
My Lady will eat later. I will help her get rested.
Your Highness, Jiang Fuhai is here.
He has something to ask on behalf of the Empress.
Show him in.
Yes.
I bow before Your Highness.
Rise.
Mr. Jiang, what perfect timing.
I was going to send for you.
Yes.
What's the background of this Fuzi?
She's got quite an attitude.
Your Highness must be jesting.
A servant doesn't have any noteworthy background.
I'm jesting?
If you want to hear a jest:
Is Fuzi disobedient to me
because the Empress is backing her?
Fuzi was newly selected by the Household Department.
She hardly served Her Majesty before coming here.
There's no such thing as "the Empress backing her".
She pulled at my hair forcibly
when grooming me the other day.
I scolded her for that, and she ran away crying.
She hasn't returned since.
I thought such were the rules she was taught
in the Empress's palace.
Your Highness, Fuzi is dead.
Dead?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Phoenix Taking Flight
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
The dreams I dimly recall;
The past I hardly remember,
amidst the autumn moons and the spring flowers.
Like the moon's reflection on water
or flowers seen through mist - floating and drifting.
The joyous sounds you brought;
The silence you left;
Changing faster than clouds can turn to rain.
Our minds resonated;
Our hearts beat in unison;
But we lost what we once possessed.
A poem to converse;
A melody to accompany;
A heart to bind to mine.
I hoped for endless longing and eternal promise,
but I’m left with only the flute and the zither.
With affection, I pleased;
With my heart, I committed;
With my arms, I embraced.
I desired to be remembered;
Desired to be cherished;
Why am I only hated and deceived?
My wish ran against my will.
Behold the mockery of destiny and the game of fate.
My unwavering love is gone
like flowers swept away in the wind.
Praying for a bright moon;
Praying for a rising sun;
Dreaming to bask in the spring breezes.
But the unsparing northern winds carry snow and rain
to destroy the aspirations of the plum tree.
A phoenix about to take flight rustles its wings
but the arc of its flight is unseen.
The phoenix tree sways in the wind,
shedding memories in the whispers of the falling leaves.